http://www.maced.org/privacy-policy/

Skip to primary navigation Skip to main content Skip to footerYou are here: Home / Privacy Policy
Your privacy is important to the Mountain Association. We have a general privacy policy for both users of our website and services. We also have a donor privacy policy listed below.
Please read these privacy notices carefully as it contains important information on who we are, how and why we collect, store, use, and share personal information, your rights in relation to your personal information and on how to contact us and supervisory authorities in the event you have a complaint.
General Privacy Policy
Who We AreThe Mountain Association collects, uses and is responsible for certain personal information about you.
Children’s Online Privacy Protection ActThis website and any products and services offered herein are not intended for persons under the age of 13. The Mountain Association does not knowingly collect information from anyone under 13 years of age. The Mountain Association prohibits children under the age of 13 from using all interactive portions of this website, including leaving any comments, filling out forms, or otherwise submitting information. The Mountain Association will not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13. If the Mountain Association learns it has any information or content from anyone under the age of 13, it will delete that information.
The Personal Information We Collect and Use
1. Information Collected by UsThe Mountain Association may collect, use, and is responsible for certain personal information that you provide when you voluntarily sign up for e-mails or free gifts, register for a class or presentation, leave comments, order a service or product, fill out any type of form, access private membership pages, or otherwise contact the
Mountain Association via an online form or e-mail. The information collected may include your name, e-mail address, physical address, phone number, and/or billing information. You are not required to provide any personally identifiable information to merely access or visit this website.
The Mountain Association may collect domain information and “cookies” (small files saved on your hard drive by your web browser) to analyze website performance, track user patterns, save information from your previous visits and customize your experience. We will ask for your consent to allow us to use cookies. The Mountain Association or its third-party vendors may collect nonpersonal information through the use of these technologies. Nonpersonal information might include the browser you use, the type of computer you use and technical information about your means of connection to this website such as the operating systems and the Internet service providers utilized and other similar information. The Mountain Association’s systems may also automatically gather information about the areas you visit and search terms you use on this website and about the links you may select from within this website to other areas of the Internet.
If you are located in the European Economic Area (EEA), we are regulated under the General Data Protection Regulation which applies across the European Union (including in the United Kingdom) and we are responsible as controller of that personal information for the purposes of those laws.
2. Information Collected from Other SourcesWe also obtain personal information from other sources, including thedatabank, Vanco, and loans.mtassociation.org.
3. How we use your personal informationThe Mountain Association collects such information in order to send e-mails, accept donations, fulfill orders, deliver services and products, complete customer transactions, oversee contests and promotions and improve website performance and customer service.
4. Who We Share Your Personal Information WithThe Mountain Association respects your privacy and will never sell, trade or transfer your personally identifiable information to third parties (beyond what is necessary for fulfilling a customer transaction or for the basic functionality of an online service) without your consent.
We do, however, share donors’/registrants’ (including persons paying for class or event registrations) personal information, such as names, mailing addresses and email addresses, only for the purposes of donor acknowledgement and/or when an individual voluntarily provides this information and opts to join the Mountain Association’s mailing list. In order to provide secure services, the Mountain Association uses third parties to process online payments. We only use third party services that match our privacy and quality standards and do not sell or share any personal identifiable information. Our current vendors include thedatabank and Vanco. Any personal identifying information is stored securely according to accounting best practice. The Mountain Association does not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. The Mountain Association employs procedures to protect our websites against known vulnerabilities and make them as safe as possible.
Those third-party recipients are based outside the European Economic Area — for further information including on how we safeguard your personal data when this occurs, see Transfer of your information out of the EEA.
The Mountain Association may release personal information to enforce its Website Terms and Conditions of Use, other Terms and Conditions, manage its business, protect users or the general public, or to otherwise comply with legal obligations.
If you give the Mountain Association your permission, we may also use personal identification information for internal or external marketing and promotional purposes.
We will not share your personal information with any other third party.
Whether Information Has to Be Provided by You and WhyWe do not require you to provide any personal data in order to view our website. We will inform you when we collect it whether you are required to provide the information to us.
How Long Your Personal Information Will Be KeptWe will hold your data for one year after any relevant audit deadlines.
Reasons We Can Collect and Use Your Personal Information
The Mountain Association collects and uses your personal information to further the following legitimate interests:  to send e-mails, fulfill orders, deliver services and products, complete customer transactions, accept donations, oversee contests and promotions and improve website performance and customer service.
Use and Transfer of Your Information Out of the EEAThis website is operated in the United States and third parties with whom we might share your personal information as explained above are also located in the United States.  If you are located in the EEA or elsewhere outside of the United States, please be aware that any information you provide will be transferred to the United States. By using this website, participating in any of its services and/or providing your information, you consent to this transfer.
The United States does not have the same data protection laws as the United Kingdom and EEA. While the European Commission has not given a formal decision that the United States provides an adequate level of data protection similar to those which apply in the United Kingdom and EEA, any transfer of your personal information will be subject to the derogation in Article 49 permitting non-repetitive transfers that concern only a limited number of data subjects, as permitted by Article 49 of the General Data Protection Regulation that is designed to help safeguard your privacy rights and give you remedies in the unlikely event of a misuse of your personal information.
If you would like further information, see “How to contact us” below.  We will not otherwise transfer your personal data outside of the EEA, or to any organization (or subordinate bodies) governed by public international law or which is set up under any agreement between two or more countries.
5. Your RightsIf you want to unsubscribe from the Mountain Association communications, you may do so at any time. Each Mountain Association email includes instructions for unsubscribing from these e-mail communications.
If you are covered by the General Data Protection Regulation, you have a number of important rights free of charge. In summary, those include rights to:
Fair processing of information and transparency over how we use your use personal information.Access to your personal information and to certain other supplementary information that this Privacy Notice is already designed to address.Require us to correct any mistakes in your information which we hold.Require the erasure of personal information concerning you in certain situations.Receive the personal information concerning you which you have provided to us, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and have the right to transmit those data to a third party in certain situations.Object at any time to processing of personal information concerning you for direct marketing.Object to decisions being taken by automated means which produce legal effects concerning you or similarly significantly affect you.Object in certain other situations to our continued processing of your personal information.Otherwise restrict our processing of your personal information in certain circumstances.
You may also have the right to claim compensation for damages caused by our breach of any data protection laws.
For further information on each of those rights, including the circumstances in which they apply, see the Guidance from the UK Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO) on individuals’ rights under the General Data Protection Regulation, available at: https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/individual-rights/ .
If you would like to exercise any of those rights, please:
Email, call, or write to us;Provide us enough information to identify you (e.g., registration or donation details)Provide us proof of your identity and address (a copy of your driver’s license or passport and a recent utility or credit card bill);Provide us with the information to which your request relates
6. Keeping Your Personal Information SecureWe have appropriate security measures in place to prevent personal information from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorized way. We limit access to your personal information to those who have a genuine business need to know it. Those processing your information will do so only in an authorized manner and are subject to a duty of confidentiality.
We will take appropriate measures to deal with any suspected data security breach. We will notify you and any applicable authorities of a suspected data security breach where we are legally required to do so.
Please note that any comments or information that you post on the website, including the Mountain Association membership site and social media pages become public and third parties may use your information. The Mountain Association is not responsible for any unauthorized uses by third parties in such context. You disclose such information at your own risk.
7. Links to Other SitesYou may see advertising or other content on this website that links to the sites and services of our partners, suppliers, advertisers, sponsors, licensors or other third parties.  Any products or services reached through a third-party link are subject to separate privacy policies. The Mountain Association is not responsible for or liable for any content on or actions taken by such third-party websites.
8. How to ComplainWe hope that we can resolve any question or concern you raise about our use of your information.
If you are covered by the General Data Protection Regulation, you may lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority, in particular in the European Union (or European Economic Area) state where you work, normally live, or where any alleged infringement of data protection laws occurred.
9. Changes to This Privacy NoticeThis policy is effective as of January 10, 2019. We may change, modify or update this Privacy Policy at any time and will notify you of any such changes by email or postal mail if we have your email or mailing address.
11. How to Contact UsIf you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy, the information we hold about you, or you wish to change your personal information in our records, please contact Mountain Association, at 433 Chestnut Street; Berea, KY 40403; 859-986-2373; info@mtassociation.org.
12. Do You Need Extra Help?If you would like this notice in another format (for example: audio, large print, braille) please contact us (see “How to contact us” above).
Mountain Association Donor Privacy Policy
The Mountain Association is committed to respecting the privacy of our donors.
Information Collected.
Here are the types of donor information that we collect and maintain:
contact information: name, organization/company, complete address, phone number, email addressdonation information: amounts donated, date of donation(s), methodyour requests and comments
Our website also collects non-personally identifiable information via  a ‘cookie’ sent to your web browser. This helps us understand how many hits each webpage receives, and if the visitor is repeat or new. For more information, see the above policy.
How Information is Used.
The Mountain Association uses your data to maintain records of donations, send acknowledgements, mail year-end tax statements to you, as well as enewsletters and direct mail pieces. We normally add you to our mailing list, unless you request otherwise.
No Sharing of Personal Information.
The Mountain Association does not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. We employ procedures to protect our websites against known vulnerabilities and make them as safe as possible.
In order to provide secure services, we use third parties to process online payments. We only use third party services that match our privacy and quality standards and do not sell or share any personal identifiable information. Our current vendors include thedatabank and Vanco. Any personal identifying information is stored securely according to accounting best practice.
We do NOT list individuals’ names in ANY of our publications. Foundation funders are occasionally listed in our annual impact report with permission.
Removing Your Name From Our Mailing List.
Please contact us if you wish to be removed from our mailing list. Email info@mtassociation.org or you can find an unsubscribe button on all of our enewsletters and news updates.
Footer
For more than 40 years, we were known as the Mountain Association for Community Economic Development (MACED).
As we enter a new decade and a new look, we have become the Mountain Association. This change underscores our commitment to a new beginning that is more inclusive and welcoming to the people and communities we serve.
Get the Newsletter
Sign Up Now
Programs
Business Support
Lending
Energy
Stories
Training & Ideas
PAINTSVILLE, KY 41240
We use cookies to ensure that we give you the best experience on our website. If you continue to use this site we will assume that you are happy with it.Ok
